hello everyone and welcome to my 4th season of GTNH
as usual the first thing we did before even starting the quest book is to rush into a place with a bed
that way we don't have to worry about the night
and now we can finally start doing the quests
so, as usual there are a bunch of annoying quests to do
and after quickly completing all of the easy quests
we got to the first quest where we can play it a little bit smarter
so we have to collect one stack of cobblestone
you could do that by just making an underground room which could be useful
but a better trick is to collect this cobblestone where it's in a way of something else
okay what I mean is that instead of randomly digging cobblestone, we can look for some ores
now if you didn't know
ores in this mod pack spawn in big veins
which are deposit every 3 by 3 chunks
okay to get a better view
you can hit F9 three times
if you hit F9 three times
you see those grids like that
at this point you should go in the middle of the 3 x 3 area
where there is this blue thing
and just dig there
now depending on how you play
you either want to make a nice staircase
or some people just dig down
turn on keep inventory and teleport
back home once they need to go back
I still haven't decided how I'm going to play this season
but I think most likely I'm just going to enable keeping inventory at this point
here I found cassiterite sand
this is an ore
if you find an ore this is ore
it doesn't say small ore
I'm going to show small ore later
this one is a full ore
that means this spawn in a vein
and if you look up in NEI, cassiterite sand
this one this is what we found
if you look it up there is this handy page
which tells you
veins stats: cassiterite sand and tin vein
now those veins spawn as huge clusters of ore
those can be almost 3 x 3 x 3 chunks big
every vein is a little bit different from the others
some are bigger, some are smaller, but they are all 9 blocks deep
the first three almost four layers of that huge deposit of ore is going to be composed of the primary ore
the bottom is going to be composed of the secondary and in between there is a lot of in-between ore too
then there is also this sporadic ore that is all around that huge chunks of ore
and there are a little bits ore here and there
usually there are like 1,000 of the primary ore in a vein
and there are like 100 of this sporadic one
that's more or less on average what a vein is made out of
now here I dug another hole in the ground
and this time I found small graphite ore
now this is a small ore
so it's not a true vein but just a small ore
but it still is very important
because for example this is a small graphite ore
now small graphite ore
to explain what I want to say
first let's look at small copper ore
so if you find a small copper ore
it has a page with small ore stats
small copper can spawn within 60 and 180 in the overworld
so if you find copper in the overworld at this height
it doesn't really mean anything
like you can find copper everywhere in those planets in this range
and this is just a single ore that spawns like that to give you a little bit of copper
now copper is meaningless
but there are other ores that you can only get in this way
so some small ores are really valuable
because that's the only way of getting something really specific
but it's mostly some rare gems
and some stuff in the late game
right now you don't really care about those small copper ores
but the thing is that if you look at these small graphite ore
small graphite ore does not have small ore stats
but we found a small graphite ore even if it does not have a small stats page
that is because when a vein spawn, it doesn't spawn only the ore vein
it also spawns some small ores of that vein all above that vein
so for example graphite is part of the graphite (vein)
okay this is another graphite vein but
it does not spawn on the overworld
so we don't look at this
that means only
this vein can be part of it because overworld
so must be this one
this vein spawns only super deep
this one spawns only super deep
but we found a small ore
quite higher up
anyways what that means is that this is not a random ore that spawns anywhere
it can only spawn above graphite and diamond veins
and that means that below this ore we can find a lot of diamonds
and that's all that ore means
but you know we found diamonds
by the way, I figure out you can right click on ore
for it to be added to the map
you don't have to break it
and after collecting enough stone
we can finally move on to the next tier
now this tier will require us to collect a lot of sand, gravel and clay
this stuff is required to make a smeltery
but the better tip is to
just go find smeltery in a village
still, you have to collect all of the stuff required by those quests
but try not to use this stuff
I mean you're going to need this stuff
so feel free to use it
think it's easier to find a village with smeltery than doing this smeltery by hand at the first time
later on
clay too
later on you will need clay for so many many things
but there are way better workarounds for clay rather than looking for clay
we will see that later
for example you will need a lot of bricks
instead of making bricks from clay
it's way easier to use the brick house
I showed at the very beginning of this video
the next quest will ask us to make a bucket
I don't like using those items, those clay buckets
but I still think it's worth it to make multiples
so don't be afraid of wasting too much stuff
there's a thing called batch crafting
batch crafting means craft way more than you need
so you won't need it later on
it's something super important in GTNH
you should always craft extra
like most of the times you should craft like 10 times what the quest asks you for
alright so I was saying trying to also calculate how much you need
to make a bucket you need 5 dusts
each dusts is made by 4 small dusts
which make from one clay
so you need a total of 20 clay balls for each bucket
so try to figure out the correct amount
also tools
make a lot of tools because you're going to eat through all of those tools really quickly
so don't craft one, craft a lot
now look at how quickly that's destroyed
many things I wanted to say
but next thing I want to say is
I hate those clay buckets
this playthrough I'm doing a bunch
this playthrough 6, probably I overdid it
I was saying sooner we will get iron buckets which are way better
there are a few downsides to those clay buckets
if you use those with lava I think they get destroyed
but right now that's the only thing we can do
there are probably ways of getting iron bucket right now
but let's follow the quest book
it's about I mean it's annoying to collect this clay
also earlier on
I said that there are better ways of getting clay
the way you should ideally use is
as soon as you can get a Steam Macerator
which should be one priority once you get to Steam Age
find a mountain made out terracotta and macerate it
it's going to be way faster and way more efficient than using a shovel to collect the small amounts of clay
oh by the way, quest rewards
my suggestion when you have to pick a choice is
you probably don't know
there are some points where there are some really useful things you could choose from
but most of the time the choice
you can figure out what to choose, almost always probably
take this quest for an instance
the only big question will be the loot bags
personally I'm not a big fan of loot bags
most of these times you get trash out of those
just take whatever you think you like the most
I think for half of the quest, there is something I'd rather take than the loot bag
and half quest where there isn't anything interesting enough
so I just take the loot bag
collecting 16 sand doesn't take that much effort
that's just food
may as well try your luck
you can get some useful stuff
okay we got food
if you look at the recipe for the loot bag
you can enchant it
getting a fortune three book in Stone Age is probably out of the question
that applies to other loot bags mostly
if you use the enchantment you get better loot
anyways if you look at the usages of the loot bag
you can see what you can actually get
and you can see the stats
for example in the Steam Age
Stone Age sorry
in the stone Age loot bag
you can basically get only foods
I mean, oh that would be nice actually I guess
collecting wood without a lumber axe is quite annoying
so that would be a thing
oh yeah one good thing about GT...
okay most people would hate it but
I like the progression where at the beginning you have a really trash axe
and later on you get the axe that can chop down a whole tree
I like that feeling of progression
you have to endure it at the beginning
but it feels rewarding once you can get the better axe
anyways what was I even doing
okay the next quest is going to make paper
the only reason I made more than one bucket is for this quest
because
if you do this thing with a single bucket
it's going to be a torture, a nightmare
I started this YouTube channel
the reason I started this YouTube channel
was because there were people making videos
crying about having to do this stuff
so I started this YouTube channel just to show that
it's not that bad
maybe it's a little bit grindy
yeah it's probably a super grindy game
if you're into grindy games it's beautiful
if you are not
I don't know what to tell you
sorry
maybe GTNH is not for you
figure out yourself, anyways
we got the logs, we can make the wood pulp
oh wait you got two per each
so technically I have enough for the quests
ah you know what
let's make more
let's batch craft
okay the thing is that
I want that 6 bucket because that way
we can't get the crafting station yet
so right now after you craft it
even if you leave the wood pulp in there
this crafting table doesn't
okay last version it will drop these on ground
now it keeps it in your inventory
cool
okay
another big thing which is not new of this version
but of the last one is that
we can do this
you can favorite a recipe
you can favorite our recipe
then you press Ctrl + Shift + A on the favorite
and here you got this thing
then if you Ctrl + scroll wheel
you can set a multiplier
then if you have all of the ingredients in your inventory
you have to press
Shift + C
so nice
so craft more paper
oh that's so good
moving things in the crafting table is super annoying to me
some people may enjoy moving things in the crafting table, I don't
I do enjoy slowly collecting wood at the beginning
I mean
after collecting enough wood I get tired of it
but I enjoy doing it at the beginning
like you can go listen to some podcast or
have something else play on the background
alright
Tinker's Construct is probably the most famous mod that is in modern Minecraft
but just in case if you don't know how those four works
first one is the stencil table
here you can decide
here you make basically those pattern things
those are parts of tools
for example I still don't have this one
you click you get this
if you have a pattern chest
this one is just a chest for those things
and if you put the next to this one
you can access the chest from this one without having to change UI
this is part builder which allows you to make
to actually make full parts
those are the patterns, here you craft things
once again this one can access your nearby chest
I think we're going to use flint and wood
not very sure probably quest book tells you what to do
what to use but
I'm guessing
so I think the quest book wants us to do
okay all of this
what does it want to do
okay pickaxe, shovel, flint axe
so you put here the pattern
here the material
here you got the thing
and finally the tool station is the thing that allows you to actually make those tools
the tool station can also be used to repair those tools
you can repair it with the material of the pickaxe
and you can add some stuff to the tools to get some extra additions
there is this book which you can easily craft
but it was also a reward
you craft it again
I got the MK2
okay here it has you a little bit of things
and also it has you the modifier you can add
to get extra bonuses
but also, more simply if you look in NEI anything like, bronze ingots
okay check the usages not the recipes
okay tool materials
here you can get the stats of those things
there are also parts but okay
I think people already know how this mod works
also if you collect 270 blocks with that pickaxe
it will level up
and gain enough your ability to collect iron ore
but pure iron ore is not easy to find
rather, it's way easier to collect some of the iron oxides
this vein for example mineral sand
is something you can directly melt into iron
and very quickly you will realize that
in this modpack, there are going to be a lot of different items
and inventory management becomes an issue
some people like to just throw everything in whatever chest they find
and then when they need something
they just use the T hotkey on NEI
and this will highlight the inventory that contain whatever you look for
but I'm not much of a fan
like I personally don't like this way of playing
I mean it really works well to find whatever you need
but I don't like chests like this one
so what I usually do is
a little bit of inventory sorting
for example here I'm going to keep all of raw ores
crashed ores
dusts
this one is going to be random blocks
stones in block form
this one is dusts
this one is organic stuff
this one is actually un-sorted things
things I still have to decide where to put
this one is for coins
and those are the 3 most important
you will want next to your crafting station
later on this one will be upgrade to crafting station
and will be able to access this chest
which will be upgraded too
and here to keep I keep all of the tools
I'm considering the buckets as tools
I keep it like I like it this way
this chest is going to have all of the useful materials
so all of the things used into craftings basically
and this one is going to be for all of the machines
I mean those are not exactly machines right now
but you should get the idea
like you need this one to be smeltery
this one is tool station and craft table
so I call those machines later on the just for machines
now one cool trick
let's say you
went back from digging stuff
okay this trick I'm going to show
the first time you will have to do it manually but
let's say you have this trash in your inventory
if you click this arrow
it's going to look for nearby inventory that have this exact item inside it
and it will put this one where there already is
so for example here I have six
here I have to click this one
oh come on, why does it not
it's a little bit glitchy
yeah there is some configuration to make it work better
I think the range is too limited
there is only
I don't know why doesn't check more containers
but you see the idea
it put the things into the correct chest
just click spam this button until it empties your inventory
I remember it getting stuck a little bit sometimes
but usually it works better than this
oh by the way
there are many different blocks you can use to build your house
there's a whole quest chapter
that is all about aesthetic blocks
it's not this one
okay this one completely overhauled
well there are many many many many blocks
most of those
a little bit too early to look into those
but doesn't take much to unlock all of the various building blocks
usually, I wait for when I get the tinker hammer that can dig nine blocks at once
and then when I will go dig a lot of ore
I will come back with a lot of cobblestone
and I'm going to use the bricks for my house
so right now I'm going to keep it like that
and I will super carefully sleep as soon as it's night
and after some more grind
we managed to make our first multiblock
multiblock because it's a structured composed of multiple blocks
alright, you probably only want one of those
it's really useful for making better fuel
I heavily suggest using the creosote oil with a bucket in furnaces
each bucket of creosote oil should smelt 32 items
you get as much fuel on creosote as you get on charcoal
mostly you don't really have any other usage for the creosote oil at this tier
and you probably want this tank to always be empty
so may as well use these on furnace
but the thing I wanted to show is that with multiblocks
for every GregTech multiblock
always remember
most likely you will always want more than one
and to save on blocks you can wall share
wall share literally means
use one wall of the multiblock to make the second
so it just goes like that
and this way this one works
we save the nine blocks by building those like that
also they just added to the game a nice guide
which explains so many things
I'm not even reading this
because most likely 99 percent of those things are things I already know about
here you can see an example of a bigger wall share
you can even make 8, you make 4 more on the back
then you can automate it
but right now we don't have access to any of this automation
so for the moment
it's only going to be useful for making some fuel
and after smelting enough iron
we can finally move on to the next quests
and once again
don't make just one tool but prepare multiples
because you are going to need multiple of those tools
also when you make plates always make way more than you probably need
and just get every tool
and with those new tools we unlock many*7 new things
now you should probably read each one of those quests
and try to understand what each of those items is
but I'm going to show you my favorite things out of all of those quests
so the first thing is going to be the new vending machine
where you can put in all of your coins
and then you can buy whatever you want
alright I think I'm too poor for any of those quests
so we will see this one again later
the next useful thing is the crafting station
this one is like a crafting table
but it can hold items when you close the UI
so you can leave things inside it
but most importantly
it can access things in a nearby chest
that way you can leave all of your tools in the associated chest
and whenever you want to craft something
you can use the NEI auto-crafting
and it will automatically pull items from the chest
send it back
good
we can also make better storage
the gold chest have way bigger storage
and we can also make barrels
those can stack many stacks of items
ideally you want to use those for like cobblestone and such
but I'm going to do those a little bit later
because they do cost a little bit of wood
right now I don't have that many items to stock
so I will make this stuff later on when I will have more materials
so I can use the materials
and I will also need this space
right now I don't need this storage space
so I'm not going to use materials for this stuff
next we have this one the lunch box
this is quite cool because
it's just to manage food but I think it's super cool
now it has different modes
you can keep it open or closed
when it's closed and you click on a chest that has food
okay
when it's in that state and you click on a chest with food
it takes the food from the chest
then you Shift + click
it closes
okay figure it out how it works
okay some point it takes food from the chest
and then you can eat it
there is a mode that allows you to edit its inventory
and a mode that you can just eat stuff inside it
that has enough space for a full food rotation
so you can't eat more than four times the same food in a row
this one helps you with that
but the thing that is probably most useful
if you don't have any luck
and the thing that I actually need now
is the ore finder
now if you cannot find some ores this one will help you
this one we need some redstone
and to get the redstone
the procedure is a little bit different from the other ores
basically you have to wash the impure redstone
you have the crushed one you can crush it again
you got the impure dust
then you throw it in a cauldron and you got the clean redstone
once you craft it
you're going to need some ore to put inside it
now you don't even need ore
you can put in this one anything that is made of what you want
I think they likely changed how it works
but yeah I'm not even too sure
I had really good luck with ores I think
I found basically everything
like I found two mica veins
one or two
but I found mica which is the rarest ore
we will need this way later on
but usually it's quite hard to find
I found a lot of diamond
anyways I did not find copper that's a weird thing
so we can take that small copper ore I found at the beginning of the stream
but did I leave it
think I didn't even collect that small copper
now wait I never found a copper ore
if you don't even have something to use in the wand
you can buy it in the vending machine
oh wait
there's a quest reward
okay
so I put this one in there
and now I'm basically going to walk around with this one in my hotbar
and it should start moving whenever I find that vein
it should have like a 64 search depth
but most ores are above 64
so unless you go on a mountain
it should work
and eventually after a lot of walking around
you should be able to find
whatever you're looking for
I mean make sure
you're looking for something that actually spawns in the dimension you're looking for
but eventually you should find it
and after looking for way longer than expected
finally found some copper ore
and I can't believe there wasn't a single copper vein
like I walked through all of that
can't believe that was the first copper vein I found
I was starting to lose hope but okay
eventually you find it
to make this one
okay look at the recipes
I don't know why it's showing this
anyways to make the ore finder wand
you basically need only iron, gold and redstone
iron is the most common ore
gold and redstone spawn as small ores a little bit everywhere
so this one should be really easy to get
those are really really easy to find
and once we have both tin and copper
we can get dust
we can get the dust out of those materials
and mix those to obtain bronze
and once we have enough bronze
we can finally craft our first small coal boiler
and with this
we are now in steam age
I think
are we?
are we not?
oh you have to do a check box
so as I was saying
and now I have to craft another
always make sure
you are following the quest
because now I have to craft another one of those for that reason
nice
so as I was saying
after we craft a second small coal boiler
we finally unlocked the steam age
and that is going to be what we will be doing in the next episode
bye bye
大家好，欢迎来到我的 GTNH 第四季
和往常一样，在开始做任务书之前，我们做的第一件事就是冲进一个有床的地方
这样我们就不用担心夜晚了
现在我们终于可以开始做任务了
和往常一样，有不少烦人的任务要做
在快速完成所有简单的任务之后
我们遇到了第一个可以智取的任务
我们需要收集一组圆石
你可以直接挖个地下室来收集圆石，地下室可能会比较有用
但更好的方式是去挖那些必经之路上的挡着的圆石
我的意思是，与其就地挖圆石，不如去探矿
热知识
这个整合包里的矿石是以大型矿脉的形式生成的
每 3x3 个区块有一个矿脉
那么要更好看到矿脉
你可以按三次 F9
按三次 F9 之后
你会看到这样的网格线
这时候你应该走到 3x3 区域的中心
那里有一个蓝色的东西
就在那里往下挖
不同的人有不同的挖法
你可以挖一个漂亮的楼梯
也有人直接往下挖
打开死亡不掉落和传送
需要回家的时候就直接传送回去
我还没想好这一季要怎么玩
我现在很大可能想的是开死亡不掉落
我在这找到了锡石矿砂
这是一种矿石
如果你找到的矿石名字里没有"贫瘠"
不叫“贫瘠xx矿石”
我稍后会展示贫瘠矿石
那就是完整的矿石
意味着它属于一个矿脉
如果你在 NEI 里查锡石砂
这个就是我们找到的
查一下，里面有一个很有用的页面
上面会告诉你
矿脉信息：锡石砂 - 锡矿脉
这些矿脉包含了大量的矿物
几乎有 3x3x3 区块那么大
但是每个矿脉都有少许不同
有的更大、有的更小，但都是9格深
这个大矿床的前三层（将近四层）由主矿石组成
底部由副矿石组成，中间则有很多中间矿石
然后还有散布在周围的零星矿石
当然到处还会分布些贫瘠矿石
通常一个矿脉里有大约 1000 个主矿石
零星矿石大约有 100 个
这就是矿脉的大致构成
现在我又在地上挖了个洞
这次我找到了贫瘠石墨矿石
这就是贫瘠矿石
它不是真正的矿脉，只是单个贫瘠矿石
但依然非常重要
比如说，这是贫瘠石墨矿石
这种贫瘠石墨矿石
让我解释一下我想说的
先来看看贫瘠铜矿石
假设你找到了一个贫瘠铜矿石
贫瘠铜矿石，它有一个贫瘠矿石信息页面
贫瘠铜矿石在主世界 Y 值 60 到 180 之间生成
所以如果你在主世界这个高度找到铜
其实说明不了什么
在这个范围内，你能在到处都找到铜
这只是一个单独生成的矿石，给你提供一点点铜
铜本身没什么大不了的
但有些矿石你只能通过这种方式获得
所以有些贫瘠矿石很珍贵
因为那是获得某些特定物品的唯一方式
不过这些主要是一些稀有宝石
以及一些后期的东西
现在你不需要太在意那些贫瘠铜矿石
但关键是，如果你看这个贫瘠石墨矿石
贫瘠石墨矿石没有贫瘠矿石信息页面
但我们确实找到了贫瘠石墨矿石，即使它没有贫瘠矿石信息页
这是因为当矿脉生成时，不只是生成矿脉本身
它还会在矿脉正上方生成该矿脉的一些贫瘠矿石
所以比如说，石墨属于石墨矿脉
好吧这是另一个石墨矿脉，但是
它不在主世界生成
所以我们不看这个
这意味只有
这个矿脉才可能，因为它生成在主世界
所以肯定是这个
这个矿脉只会生成在非常深的地方
这个只会生成在非常深的地方
但我们在很浅的地方
找到了一个贫瘠矿石
无论如何，这意味着这不是一个在任意地方随机生成的矿石
它只会在石墨和钻石矿脉上方生成
这也就意味着在这个矿石下方，我们能找到大量钻石
这就是这个贫瘠矿石的全部含义
你看，我们确实找到了钻石
顺便说一下，我发现你可以右键点击矿石
把它添加到地图上
不需要挖掉它
收集了足够的石头之后
我们终于可以进入下一个阶段了
这个阶段需要我们收集大量的沙子、沙砾和黏土
这些东西是用来造冶炼炉的
但更好的建议是
直接去村庄里找一个冶炼炉
不过，你还是得收集任务要求的所有材料
但尽量别用掉它们
呃，你以后会需要的它们的
所以还是想用就用吧
但是我觉得一周目找个有冶炼炉的村子比手动做一个容易多了
之后
黏土是也一样
以后你会需要大量的黏土做各种东西
但有比挖黏土好得多的替代方法
我们之后会讲到
比如你会需要很多砖头
与其用黏土烧砖
不如直接用砖房里的砖，容易得多
砖房我这个视频开头展示过
下一个任务要求我们做一个桶
我不喜欢用那些黏土桶
但我还是觉得多做几个是值得的
所以别怕浪费材料
有一种玩法叫批量合成
批量合成就是做得比你目前需要的多得多
这样以后就不用再做了
这在 GTNH 里非常重要
你应该总是多做
大多数时候你应该做任务要求的十倍的量
好吧，我刚想说也计算一下你需要多少材料
做一个桶你需要5个粉
每个粉由4个小撮粉组成
一个黏土可以做一个小撮粉
所以每个桶总共需要20个黏土球
所以算好正确的数量
哦对了，还有 GT 工具
多做一些 GT 工具，因为它们消耗得飞快
所以别只做一个，做一堆
看，消耗得多快
还有很多我想说的
但接下来我想说的是
我讨厌那些黏土桶
这周目我做了不少
做了6个，可能做多了
刚才我想说，很快我们就能做出铁桶，比黏土桶好用得多
黏土桶有几个缺点
如果你用它装岩浆，它好像会坏掉
但现在我们只能用它
现在可能有好几个办法搞到铁桶
但我们还是跟着任务书走吧
但是收集这些黏土很烦人
还有，在之前
我说有更好的方法获取黏土
理想的方法就是
等你能做出蒸汽粉碎机的时候
这应该是你进入蒸汽时代后优先做的事
找一座陶瓦山，把它打粉
这样比用铲子挖黏土快得多、效率高得多
哦对了，任务奖励
当你要做选择的时候，我的建议是
你可能不知道选什么
有些任务奖励里会有非常好的东西可选
但大多数时候
你应该能看出该选什么，可能基本都能
拿这个任务举个例子
唯一需要纠结的就是战利品袋
我个人不太喜欢战利品袋
大部分时候开出来的都是垃圾
所以选你最喜欢的就好
我觉得差不多一半的任务，有比战利品袋更好的选择
另一半任务没什么特别有趣的
那就拿战利品袋好了
收集16个沙子不费什么功夫
这就是个食物罢了
不如碰碰运气
可能会开出有用的东西
好吧，开出的是食物
如果你看一下战利品袋的配方
你可以给它附魔
在石器时代弄到时运三附魔书应该不太可能
这个主要适用于其他阶段的战利品袋
给战利品袋附魔可以开出更好的东西
不管怎样，如果你查战利品袋的用途
就能看到能开出什么东西
还能看到概率
比如在蒸汽时代……
不对，石器时代，不好意思
在石器时代的战利品袋
基本上只能开出食物
哦，其实这个木头也还行
没有伐木斧的时候砍树挺烦的
所以这也不错
哦对，关于格雷科技的一个乐趣是……
好吧大多数人可能会讨厌
但我喜欢这种升级过程：一开始你拿着很垃圾的斧头
后来你拿到能砍整棵树的斧头
我喜欢这种逐渐升级的感觉
一开始你得忍着
但当你拿到更好的斧头时，会感觉很有成就感
算了，我到底在干嘛来着
好的，下一个任务是要造纸
我做几个桶的唯一原因就是为了这个任务
因为
如果你只用一只桶来做这事
那简直就是折磨，噩梦
我开这个油管频道
我开这个频道的原因
是因为有些人做视频
抱怨说要做这些事太痛苦了
所以我开了这个频道来证明
其实没那么糟糕
可能确实有点肝
对，这游戏确实挺肝的
如果你喜欢肝的游戏，那就太棒了
如果你不喜欢
那我也没什么好说的
抱歉
也许 GTNH 不适合你
自己看着办吧
我们有原木了，可以做木浆了
等一下，是一出二吗
所以按道理我已经做够了
啊，算了
再多做点
批量合成
好吧，问题是
我想要6个桶，因为那样的话
现在我们还没有合成站
所以现在你合成完之后
即使你把木浆留在工作台里
这个工作台不会……
好吧，上个版本它会掉到地上
现在会保留在你的物品栏里
酷
好的
另一个重要功能，虽然不是这个版本新增的
上个版本就有了
我们可以这样做
你可以收藏一个配方
（删）
然后对着收藏按 Ctrl + Shift + A
这里就会出现这个东西
然后如果你用 Ctrl + 滚轮
可以设置数量
如果你的物品栏里有所有材料
你需要按
Shift + C
不赖
再多做点纸
哦牛批
在工作台里移动物品对我来说特别烦人的
有些人可能喜欢在工作台里挪东西
我倒是挺享受一开始慢慢砍树的
砍着砍着
木头够了之后我确实会厌倦
我享受的是一开始的那种感觉
比如你可以边听播客
或者在后台放点别的东西
好
匠魂大概是现代 MC 里最著名的 mod 了
但以防有人不知道这四个东西怎么用
第一个是模具加工台
在这里你可以决定……
在这里你可以做那些模具
那些是工具部件
比如说我还没有这个
点一下就能做出来
如果你有个模具箱
这个就是专门放模具的箱子
如果你把它放在模具台旁边
你就可以在模具台里直接访问模具箱里的物品，不用切换界面
这是部件加工台
用来真正做出工具部件
这些是模具，你在右边这里合成东西
同样的，这个也能访问旁边的模具箱
我想我们要用燧石和木头做
不太确定，可能任务书里会告诉怎么做
用什么材料，不过
我在瞎猜
我觉得任务书想让我们做
好吧，这些
它到底想让我们做什么
好，镐、铲子、燧石斧
所以你把模具放到这里
这里是材料
拿到成品
最后，工具组装台是让你真正制作这些工具的东西
工具组装台也可以用来修理那些工具
你可以用镐头的材料修理它
你也可以在工具中添加一些额外材料来获得额外效果
有一本你可以简单做出来的书
但它也是任务奖励
再次合成一下
做出第二辑
好吧，这书里说了一些东西
它展示了你可以添加的强化
来获得额外加成
但更简单的是，如果你在 NEI 里搜，比如青铜锭
好吧，查用途而不是配方
工具材料
在这里你可以得到这些东西的数据
也有部件
我觉得大伙已经知道这个 mod 怎么玩了
另外，如果你用镐挖了 270 个方块
它会升级的
升级会获得足够的挖掘等级来收集铁矿石
但纯铁矿石不容易找到
相反，收集一些氧化铁要容易得多
例如矿砂
它是可以直接烧成铁的东西
很快你就会意识到
在这个整合包中，会有很多不同的物品
仓库管理成为一个问题
有些人喜欢把找到的东西都扔进箱子里
然后当他们需要什么的时候
他们就在 NEI 上按 T 键
这将高亮显示存放了你所查找的东西的容器
但我不太喜欢
我个人不喜欢这种方法
虽然这样找到你需要的东西真的很管用
但是我不喜欢箱子变成这样
所以我通常的做法是
一定程度的库存分类
比如，这里放所有粗矿
粉碎矿
矿粉
杂物方块
石头方块
石头粉
这个是有机的东西
这个是未分类的东西
我还没决定放在哪里的东西
这个给是硬币用的
这是最重要的三个箱子
你要把它们放在合成站旁边
之后我会升级它为合成站
并且能够访问这个箱子
这个箱子也会升级
我把所有的工具放这个箱子
我觉得桶也算工具
呃……就放着吧，我觉得挺好
这个箱子是有所有有用的材料
基本上是所有用于合成的东西
这个放所有机器类的
现在这些还不完全是机器
但你应该懂我意思
就像你需要这个来搭出冶炼炉一样
这个是工具站和工作台
我把他们算机器类，以后肯定都是机器了
有一个很酷的技巧
比如说你
下完矿回来
好吧我要展示的这个技巧
第一次你必须手动完成，但是
假设你的箱子中有这些垃圾
如果你点击这个箭头
它会寻找附近有这个相同物品的容器
并把身上的物品放在已有该物品的地方
例如，这里我有六个
在这里，我点这个
草，怎么没用
有点小故障
是的，你可以动一下配置让它更好地工作
我觉得范围太有限了
只有……
是的，我不知道为什么不检查更多的容器
但你应该懂我意思了
它会把东西放在正确的箱子里
只需狂按这个按钮，直到它清空你的背包
我记得它有时候会有点卡
但通常它比刚刚的效果好
哦对了
有许多可以用来建房子的方块
有一整章的任务
关于装饰/建筑方块的
不是这个
好吧，这任务书被大改了
嗯，有很多很多很多的方块
大多数那些
对于现在来说还有点太早
但做出所有这些不同的方块不怎么费工夫
通常我会等到做出能同时挖九个方块的匠魂锤子
然后我去挖很多矿石的时候
我会带着很多圆石回来
我打算用石砖建房子
所以现在我先就这样
我会非常谨慎地一到晚上就睡觉
肝了一会
我们做出了第一个多方块机器
叫它多方块，是因为它是由多个方块组成的
好吧，现在你可能只想造一个
它对制造更好的燃料非常有用
我强烈建议用杂酚油桶做熔炉燃料
每桶杂酚油可以烧 32 个物品
木炭和杂酚油能提供同样多的燃料
这个时期的杂酚油基本上没有其他用途
你可能希望这个仓室永远是空的
所以不妨在熔炉里烧掉
但我想展示的是多方块
对于所有的 GT 多方块
永远记住
大概率你总是要造不止一个
为了节省方块，你可以共用结构方块
共用结构方块的字面意思：
把一个多方块的一整面给第二个多方块用
就像这样
这样就可以了
这样搭可以省九个方块
他们还在游戏中添加了一个不错的指南
解释了很多东西
我都没读这个
因为很有可能 99% 的东西是我已经知道的
在这里你可以看到一个更大的共用结构方块的例子
你甚至可以做8个机器，背面再做4个
然后你可以自动化它
不过现在我们无法做出自动化
所以目前
它只用来制造燃料
烧出足够的铁之后
我们终于可以继续下一个任务了
再一次
不要只做一个 GT 工具，多做点
因为你将需要很多 GT 工具
另外，当你制作板子时，总是做比你可能需要的要多得多
把所有工具都造出来
使用这些新工具，我们可以解锁非常非常多新东西
你应该把每个任务说明都读一遍
并尝试了解每一个物品是什么
但我将向你们展示这些任务中我最喜欢的东西
第一个是新的自动售货机
在这你可以放入所有硬币
然后你可以买任何你想要的东西
好吧，我太穷了，无法完成这些任务
所以我们后面再看看
下一个有用的东西是合成站
这个就像工作台
但它可以在你关闭 UI 时保存物品
所以你可以把东西留在里面
但最重要的是
它可以访问附近箱子里的东西
这样你就可以把所有的工具都放在旁边的箱子里
你想制作一些东西的时候
你可以用 NEI 的自动合成
它会自动从箱子里取出物品
放回去
好
我们还可以做更好的存储
金箱子有更大的储物空间
我们还可以做木桶（抽屉）
它们可以放很多组同类物品
理想情况下，你可以用它存圆石之类的
但是我稍后会再做这些
因为做它确实需要一些木头
现在我没有那么多东西要存
我之后会在有更多的材料时做这些东西
这样我就可以用掉这些材料
我也需要这个储存空间
现在我不需要这个储物空间
所以我不会用这些材料
接下来是这个午餐盒
这很酷，因为
它只有管理食物的功能，但我觉得超级酷
它有不同的模式
你可以打开或关闭它
当它关闭时，你用它点击一个有食物的箱子
好吧
当它在这个状态的时候左键一个有食物的箱子
它就会把食物从箱子里拿出来
然后你 Shift 右键
它关闭了
好吧，你可以自己弄清楚它是怎么用的
好吧，它能从箱子里获取食物
然后你就可以吃了
一个模式允许你编辑它的库存
另一种模式，你可以吃里面的东西
它有足够的空间进行完整的食物轮换
你不能连续吃超过四次相同的食物
用这个可以帮你避免
但最有用的可能是
如果你运气不好
我现在真正需要的是
探矿魔杖
如果你找不到一些矿石，探矿魔杖会派上用场
做这个魔杖我们需要一些红石
要获得红石
步骤与其他矿物有点不同
基本上你要洗含杂红石
你有了粉碎红石，可以再粉碎一次
你会得到含杂粉
然后你把它扔进坩埚，你就得到了干净的粉
你制作完之后
你需要把一种矿石放在里面
现在你甚至不需要矿石了
你可以在这个里面放任何你想要的东西
我认为他们可能改变它的用法
但是，好吧，我不太确定
我在探矿方面的运气很好
我基本上什么都找到了
就像我发现了两条云母矿脉
一个还是两个来着
反正我发现了最稀有的云母矿
我们在很久之后会用上它
但通常很难找到
我发现了很多钻石
不管怎样，我没有找到铜，这很怪
所以我们可以用上刚开始录时发现的贫瘠铜矿
但我存它了吗？
我好像甚至没有收集那个贫瘠铜矿
等等，我从来没有找到过铜矿石
如果你连魔杖里可以用的东西都没有
你可以在自动售货机里买到
哦等等
有任务奖励
好吧
那么我把这个放在上面
现在我基本上是把它放在快捷栏里走来走去
只要我找到那矿脉，它就会有反应
它应该有 64 格的搜索深度
但大多数矿石都在 Y=64 以上
所以除非你去山上
它应该都是有效的
最终，在走了这么远之后
你应该能找到你在找什么矿
（向上合并）
哦对了，你要确保
你找的东西会在你要找的维度中生成
但最终你应该能找到它
在花了比预期长得多的时间寻找后
我们终于找到了一些铜矿
我不敢相信这里没有一条铜矿脉
我这一片都走遍了
真不敢相信这是我发现的第一条铜矿脉
我开始失去希望了，但没关系
都能找到的
要做这个
好吧，看看配方
我不知道为什么会显示这个
无论如何，要制作探矿魔杖
你基本上只需要铁、金和红石
铁是最常见的矿石
黄金和红石到处都是贫瘠矿石
所以这个应该很容易做出来
那些矿真的很容易找到
一旦我们有了锡和铜
我们可以做出粉
我们可以从材料中得到粉
并将它们混合，获得青铜
一旦我们有了足够的青铜
我们终于可以制造出第一台小型燃煤锅炉了
有了这个
我们就进入蒸汽时代了
我觉得
对吗？
不对？
哦，你必须点一个复选框
正如我所说
现在我必须制作另一个
始终确保
你在跟着任务书走
因为现在我必须为此制作另一个锅炉
很好
正如我所说
在我们制造出第二台小型燃煤锅炉后
我们终于进入了蒸汽时代
而这将是我们在下一集要做的
拜拜